When we want to configure our gateway, we first need to select the packet forwarder what we want to use.
We usually don't have a lot of choice because the gateway may not support all packet forwarder.
And on the other side, the network server also doesn't support all packet forwarder .
Once we've chosen the most appropriate packet forwarder, we need to install it on the gateway. All packet
forwarder designers provide information to manage this process.
For example, if you've chosen a Loriot packet forwarder, then you need to go on their website to follow
the procedure to install the software.
On this page,
for example, they provide the instructions for Kerlink iFemtocell gateway and we'll have to follow
the steps described in this section.
And for the same Kerlink iFemtocell gateway, if you want to use or to connect your gateway on
Actility network server, then again, you need to go on the network server website and they will
provide a way to set up the packet forwarder.
In that case, you can download the new gateway firmware to connect Thingpark, which is the Actility's
network server.
Okay.
But for our lecture, we'll often use the most common and probably the easiest packet forwarder to configure.
Indeed, it's pretty convenient to make the demonstration with the original Semtech packet forwarder
because it's supported by almost all network servers. And most of the time this packet forwarder is also
active by default on the gateways.
So even if we will show you later in this course a demonstration with other packet forwarder, we just
let you know that most of the configuration demonstration will be made with the original Semtech
packet forwarder.
Okay, so now what are the two important information we need to enter?
First, it's the IP address of the network server,
then the UDP port.
These can be done in several ways, depending on the gateway you have.
Some gateways have a small web service and we can connect to our gateway with our computer, thanks
to a classic web page.
Here is an example of an indoor gateway from Strataggem.
I just need to push a small button to enter the web service.
Then I can even use the gateway name in the URL to access the website.
I just need to change these four characters to specify my own hardware.
Or if I wanted, I could have used the gateway IP address if it was more convenient.
And anyway, we end up on the configuration web page and in this corresponding section here, there
is the LoRaWAN configuration.
We have fields where we can enter the IP address of the network server.
We can even use the network server URL if the gateway uses a DNS server.
And of course, there is also the fields for the port numbers. Right?
That was the first kind of gateway configuration.
Another method is often to connect to the gateway with an ssh client.
Once connected, there will be either a command or a file to modify to change the name of the targeted
network server.
Let's try an example with an indoor Kerlink iFemtocell gateway.
I'm connected with my client and in the prompt here is the command to modify the targeted network server.
Finally, a third possibility is to connect to the gateway with a serial link.
For that, we need to use a serial terminal and to send the right command.
Here.
I've got an 1832 nuclear gateway for this hardware.
We have to send a specific command provided in the documentation.
By default, we can see that the network server configured is Loriot with port number 1780.
And with this gateway, if we want to charge the server, I need to use the following command.
AT+PKTFWD= the IP address of the network server.
Then we enter the port number we want.
If we reset the gateway, we can see that it's been saved with the right network server.
In this example TTN. I'm done with the gateway configuration so we can carry on with the second step,
which is the gateway registration on the network server.